dropcam.com 2011-10-13

# Privacy policy | Dropcam

* * *

Last modified on 3 April 2011 Recent updates to this Privacy Policy may be found here.

* * *

Welcome to Dropcam, the application, website, and online services of Dropcam, Inc. ("Dropcam," "we," or "us"). Dropcam values the privacy of its users who have Member accounts ("you" or "Users"). Dropcam knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by Dropcam when you use the Dropcam Service, how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy are defined in our Terms of Use Agreement.

By using the Service, you expressly consent to the information-handling practices described in this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Service and any personal information you provide through the Service are subject at all times to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use Agreement.

## Information We Collect

User-Provided Information: You provide us information about yourself (such as your name and e-mail address) if you register for a Member account with the Service, or as you use the features and functionality of the Service, including by uploading User Content. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses. We may also retain any messages you send through the Service.

Cookies Information: When you visit the Service, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and allows Dropcam to help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey anonymous information about how you browse the Service to us. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. Dropcam uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser's directions; please check your web browser's Help Settings to learn how you can modify your cookie settings. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

Log File Information: Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you register with or view our site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, referring/exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

Clear Gifs Information: When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our Users anonymously. No personally identifiable information from your Member account is collected using these clear gifs. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our Users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make Dropcam better for our Users.

## How We Use Your Information

We use the personal information you submit to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service.

By providing Dropcam your email address you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. You also agree that we may send you notifications of activity on the Service to the email address you give us. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, such as newsletters, changes to features of the Service, or special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out or change your preferences in your "My Account" page. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers. You may not opt out of Service-related e-mails.

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service (including your User Content) becomes available to Dropcam and any other Members authorized by you to share the information or content. If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information.

Following termination or deactivation of your Member account, Dropcam may retain your profile information and User Content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes. Furthermore, Dropcam may retain and continue to use indefinitely all information (including User Content) contained in your communications to other Users or in your postings to public areas of the Service after termination or deactivation of your Member account.

If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to the Service, we will ask you for that person's email address and automatically send an email invitation. Dropcam stores this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our invitation service. Your friend may contact us to request that we remove this information from our database at [privacy@dropcam.com](mailto:privacy@dropcam.com).

Dropcam may use certain information about you and/or your User Content without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content.

Dropcam reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the User Content you post on the Service. We reserve the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Use Agreement, or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. Dropcam also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to:

  1. remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site;
  2. provide custom, personalized content and information;
  3. monitor the effectiveness of our Service;
  4. monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns;
  5. diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our Users or engineers that are associated with certain IP addresses;
  6. help you efficiently access your information after you sign in;
  7. operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on the Service;
  8. track User Content and Users to the extent necessary to comply as a service provider with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act; and
  9. automatically update the Dropcam application on your system, cameras, and related devices.

## How We Share Your Information

Personally Identifiable Information: Dropcam will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others. Dropcam may share your personally identifiable information with third parties solely for the purpose of providing the Service to you. If we do this, such third parties' use of your information will be bound by this Privacy Policy. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of Dropcam (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

We will Share your Video Content with other Members as directed by you via the functionality of the Service.

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

From time to time, we may run contests, special offers, or other events or activities ("Events") on the Service together with a third-party partner. If you provide information to such third parties, you give them permission to use it for the purpose of that Event and any other use that you approve. We cannot control third parties' use of your information. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with a third party, you can choose not to participate in these Events.

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, Dropcam will not disclose personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena, or if we believe that such action is necessary to:

  1. conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities;
  2. to enforce our Terms of Use Agreement, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and
  3. to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Dropcam, our Users or others.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information: We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain Dropcam services.

Dropcam may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Service. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on Dropcam. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content. Dropcam does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks Dropcam to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. Dropcam's Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party advertisers. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers for more information.

## How We Protect Your Information

Dropcam uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information and User Content. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Dropcam, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, Dropcam makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information or User Content may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from Dropcam, at all times.

## Compromise of Personal Information

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Dropcam will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

## Your Choices About Your Information

You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the Service, in which case Dropcam may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update or correct your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account. You can review and correct the information about you that Dropcam keeps on file by contacting us directly at [privacy@dropcam.com](mailto:privacy@dropcam.com).

## Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Dropcam does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of thirteen (13) or knowingly allow such persons to register as Members. If you are under thirteen (13) years of age, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age thirteen (13) is allowed to provide any personal information to or on Dropcam. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age thirteen (13) without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as promptly as reasonably possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under thirteen (13) years of age, please contact us at [privacy@dropcam.com](mailto:privacy@dropcam.com).

## Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

## Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our website, as determined by Dropcam in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our website to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at [privacy@dropcam.com](mailto:privacy@dropcam.com), or send mail to:  
Dropcam, Inc.  
160 Spear Street  
Suite 1700  
San Francisco, CA 94105

* * *

**Updates**  
April 3, 2011: changing 88Volts, Inc. references to Dropcam, Inc.
